Guide to the Moorefield Station collection, 2001-2003
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives.
Moorefield Station collection
2001-2003
C0258
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections Research Center.
2 linear ft.
The collection consists of a developers' packet, compact disks, and a Zoning Map Amendment Application for Moorefield Station, a planned community in Loudoun County, Virginia.
Claude Moore Charitable Foundation.
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by George Mason University Libraries before 2008.
Historical Information
The planned community of Moorefield Station is located less than ten miles northwest of Dulles International Airport in Loudoun County, Virginia. It is a project of the Claude Moore Charitable Foundation, which takes its name and mission from Loudoun County doctor Claude Moore (1892-1991). As the developers' packet for Moorefield Green notes, the community was envisioned as a walkable, sustainable development, "a model for 'smart growth.' " As of 2015, Moorefield Station continues to be a work in progress.
Scope and Content
The bulk of the collection is a 14-volume Zoning Map Amendment Application that includes the application, exhibits, an environmental report, and a traffic study, as well as two later submissions of the revised application. The collection also contains a developers' packet for Moorefield Green, a precinct within the Moorefield Station community, as well as 9 compact disks that include photos, design, engineering, zoning, environmental, and historical information. Materials date from 2001-2003.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by format. The Zoning Map Amendment Application is arranged numerically by volume.
Index Terms
Geographical Names:
Loudoun County (Va.)
Subjects:
Planned communities.; Planning--Virginia, Northern.
Contents List
- Moorefield Station collection
  - Welcome to Moorefield Green - an Escape to Loudoun Tradition" Developers' Packet (includes information on 9 compact disks), 2003 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 1, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 2 (Exhibits), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 3 (Preliminary [phase 1] environmental assessment, 1993), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 4 (Preliminary [phase 1] environmental assessment, 1993), 2001 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 5 (Traffic Impact Analysis), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 6 (Traffic Impact Analysis), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 7 (Traffic Impact Analysis), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 8 (Traffic Impact Analysis), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 9 (Traffic Impact Analysis), 2001 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 10 (Revised Zoning Map Amendment Application and Exhibits), March 2002 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 11 (Revised Traffic Impact Analysis), March 2002 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 12 (Revised Traffic Impact Analysis), March 2002 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 13 (Revised Traffic Impact Analysis), March 2002 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Moorefield Station Zoning Map Amendment Application - Volume 14 (Revised Zoning Map Amendment Application and Exhibits, June 2002 (Box 4, Folder 3)